Can a great man be a good man?
Steve Jobs is a drama, history film directed by Danny Boyle.
Set backstage at three iconic product launches and ending in 1998 with the unveiling of the iMac, Steve Jobs takes us behind
the scenes of the digital revolution to paint an intimate portrait of the brilliant man at its epicenter.
Steve Jobs, played by Michael Fassbender.
Joanna Hoffman, played by Kate Winslet.
Steve Wozniak, played by Seth Rogen.
John Sculley, played by Jeff Daniels.
Andy Hertzfeld, played by Michael Stuhlbarg.
Chrisann Brennan, played by Katherine Waterston.
Steve Jobs is a 2015 biographical drama film directed by
Danny Boyle and written by Aaron Sorkin.
A British-American co-production, it was adapted from the 2011 biography
by Walter Isaacson and interviews conducted by Sorkin.
The film covers fourteen years in the life of Apple Inc.
co-founder Steve Jobs, specifically ahead of three press conferences he gave during that time: the formal unveiling of the Macintosh 128K on
January 24, 1984; the unveiling of the NeXT Computer on October 12, 1988; and the unveiling of the iMac G3 on May 6, 1998.
Jobs is portrayed by Michael Fassbender, with Kate Winslet as Joanna Hoffman, Seth Rogen
as Steve Wozniak, and Jeff Daniels as John Sculley in supporting roles.
Development began in 2011 after the rights to Isaacson's book were acquired.
Filming began in January 2015.
A variety of actors were considered and cast before
Fassbender eventually took the role.
Editing was extensive on the project, with editor Elliot
Graham starting while the film was still shooting.
Daniel Pemberton served as composer, with a focus on dividing
the score into three distinguishable sections.
Steve Jobs premiered at the 2015 Telluride Film Festival on September 5, 2015, and began
a limited release in New York City and Los Angeles on October 9, 2015.
It opened nationwide in the United States on October 23, 2015, to widespread critical acclaim, with Boyle's direction, visual style, Sorkin's
screenplay, musical score, cinematography, editing and the acting of Fassbender, Winslet, Rogen and Daniels garnering unanimous acclaim.
However, it was a financial disappointment, grossing only $34.4
million worldwide against a budget of $30 million.
People close to Jobs such as Steve Wozniak and John Sculley praised the
performances, but the film also received criticism for historical inaccuracy.
Steve Jobs was nominated for Best Actor (Fassbender) and Best Supporting Actress
(Winslet) at the 88th Academy Awards, and received numerous other accolades.
The film explores themes of computer, biography, based on true
story, father daughter relationship, wonder.
The tone is emotional and intense.